export default Dpe8 = [
    {
        question: "1. The bond present between two 'N' atoms is ",
        options: ["Double covalent bond",
            "None",
            "Triple covalent bond",
            "Single covalent bond"],
        correct_option: "Triple covalent bond"
    },
    {
        question: "2. The bond angle in water molecule is",
        options: ["109°28¹",
            "80°",
            "20°",
            "104°28¹"],
        correct_option: "104°28¹"
    },
    {
        question: "3. Negative particles in atom are",
        options: ["Nutreon",
            "Electrons",
            "one",
            "rotons"],
        correct_option: "Electrons"
    },
    {
        question: "5. The bond in H2O is",
        options: ["Covalent",
            "Polar",
            "Coordinate",
            "Ionic"],
        correct_option: "Polar"
    },

    {
        question: "6. A pi bond is formed by ..............overlap of orbitals",
        options: ["Can't form",
            "Axial",
            "Without overlapping",
            "Lateral"],
        correct_option: "Lateral"
    },
    {
        question: "7. The shape of the ammonia molecule is",
        options: ["Pyramidal",
            "Linear",
            "Trigonal planar",
            "Tetrahedral"],
        correct_option: "Pyramidal"
    },
    {
        question: "8. Arrange the following in a systematic order \n" +
            "1.Formation of anions \n" +
            "2.Electrostatic force of attraction \n" +
            "3.Formation of ionic bond \n" +
            "4.Formation of cation",
        options: ["4 , 1 , 2 , 3",
            "4 , 2 , 1 , 3",
            "1 , 2 , 3 , 4",
            "1 , 4 , 3 , 2"],
        correct_option: "4 , 1 , 2 , 3"
    },
    {
        question: "9. In the formation of MgCl2 number of electrons transferred from Mg to cl is",
        options: ["1",
            "2",
            "4",
            "3"],
        correct_option: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "10. Which of the following is the bond angle of Methane (CH4) ?",
        options: ["120°",
            "104°31¹",
            "109°28¹",
            "107°48¹"],
        correct_option: "109°28¹"
    },
    {
        question: "11. Ionic compound in the following is.........",
        options: ["H2",
            "C2H6",
            "HCL",
            "NaCl"],
        correct_option: "NaCl"
    },

    {
        question: "12. Which of the following is the shape of methane molecule ?",
        options: ["Trigonal - Planar",
            "V-shape",
            "Trigonal - Pyramidal",
            "Tetrahedron"],
        correct_option: "Tetrahedron"
    },
    {
        question: "13. Which of the following hybridization is there in beryllium chloride (BeCl2) molecule ?",
        options: ["sp2",
            "None",
            "sp3",
            "sp"],
        correct_option: "None"
    },
    {
        question: "14. Electrons are negatively charged and they -----------------each other.",
        options: ["Repel",
            "Neither attract nor repel",
            "None",
            "Attract"],
        correct_option: "Repel"
    },
    {
        question: "15. These ions lose electrons to form stable positive ions",
        options: ["Cations",
            "Anions",
            "Both anions & cations",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Cations"
    },
    {
        question: "16. Valency expresses.",
        options: ["Atomicity of an element",
            "Total electrons in valence shell of an atom and Combining capacity of an element",
            "Combining capacity of an element",
            "Total electrons in valence shell of an atom"],
        correct_option: "Total electrons in valence shell of an atom and Combining capacity of an element"
    },
    {
        question: "17. Which of the following elements are electro negative ?",
        options: ["Sodium",
            "Oxygen",
            "Calcium",
            "Magnesium"],
        correct_option: "Oxygen"
    },
    {
        question: "18. Chemical formula of methane is",
        options: ["C4H4",
            "CH4",
            "C2H2",
            "C2H6"],
        correct_option: "CH4"
    },
    {
        question: "19. The covalency of O2 is..",
        options: ["1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"],
        correct_option: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "20. Which of the following element has most electronegativity ?",
        options: ["Bromine",
            "Cesium",
            "Chlorine",
            "Fluorine"],
        correct_option: "Fluorine"
    },

    {
        question: "21. Hybridization was proposed by",
        options: ["Both Gillespie & Nyholm",
            "Gillespie",
            "Chadwick",
            "Nyholm"],
        correct_option: "Both Gillespie & Nyholm"
    },
    {
        question: "22. The atomic number of an element 'y' is 19 , the formula of its oxide is ...",
        options: ["YO",
            "Y2O",
            "YO2",
            "Y2O3"],
        correct_option: "Y2O"
    },
    {
        question: "23. These elements exist as atoms but not molecule",
        options: ["Alkaline - earth metals",
            "Metals",
            "Inert gases",
            "Halogen"],
        correct_option: "Inert gases"
    },
    {
        question: "24. Who proposed the ionic bond ?",
        options: ["Kossel",
            "Powell",
            "Sidgwick",
            "G.N.Lewis"],
        correct_option: "Kossel"
    },
    {
        question: "25. The formula for methane is",
        options: ["C4H4",
            "C2H2",
            "CH4",
            "C2H6"],
        correct_option: "C2H6"
    },
]